AMY CHEN

Seattle, WA | 206-688-0434 | <u>amychen.dev@gmail.com</u> | <u>www.amychen.dev</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/4myc</u> | Blog: <u>dev.to/4myc</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/4myc</u>

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Versatile front-end engineer with full-stack capability and a background in graphic and web design.

Eager and quick learner keen on utilizing my creative and technical skills to create visually engaging user interfaces and experiences. Passionate about combining code and design to make an impact on users' lives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT-END JavaScript Rails React.js PostgreSQL Ruby SQLite HTML RESTful APIs CSS Git Material UI Semantic UI Bootstrap

DESIGN SKILLS

User Interface Design
Responsive Web Design
Graphic Design
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe InDesign

EDUCATION

10/2019 - 03/2020

Flatiron School

Seattle, WA

Full Stack Web Development In-Person Program

06/2006 - 03/2010

The Art Institute of Seattle

Seattle, WA

BFA, Graphic Design

08/2005 - 05/2006

University of Central Arkansas

Conway, AR General Studies

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Trip Planner

GitHub Client | GitHub Server

Dynamic single-page app that allows a user to create trips and add a packing list and itinerary to each trip.

- + Collaborated with two team members and built the CRUD app within a 7-day timeline
- + Contributions: Trips page layout and design, new user form, toggle function to view a trip's edit forms, installed and set up Semantic UI, added back-end user validation
- + Utilized Semantic UI interactive elements to style Trips page user interface and improve user experience
- + Front-End: React.js, Semantic UI
- + Back-End: Rails, PostgreSQL

Leopardy!

GitHub Repo

CLI trivia game about leopards inspired by Jeopardy! and Pup Quiz from The Tonight Show Starring Jimmy Fallon.

- + Full CRUD app built within a 4-day timeline
- + Implemented logic to allow the user to create, update, and delete an account
- + Implemented logic to create three multiple-choice game rounds
- + Incorporated ASCII logo and visual design elements to improve user experience
- + Technologies: Ruby, ActiveRecord

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer 06/2020 - Present

Win My Vote | Seattle, WA

Bookline Production Assistant 11/2018 - 09/2019

Reischling Press Incorporated | Tukwila, WA

Production Specialist & Graphic Designer 09/2010 - 04/2013

content26 | Seattle, WA